An Inventory of the Abraham D. Sofaer Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Abraham D. Sofaer Papers
1934-2007
96040
Sofaer, Abraham D.
149 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes 61.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The Abraham D. Sofaer Papers record his accomplishments as a legal adviser, a judge, a professor, and a writer. The most important segment of this collection is his handling of the libel suit brought against Time magazine by Ariel Sharon in 1984. He also deals with the international laws of warfare and the presidential war-making powers in the United States. The legal interpretation of the 1972 Anti Ballistic Missile Treaty and its effects on development of the Strategic Defense Initiative form a significant part of his legal proceedings. Materials include writings, reports, notes, studies, correspondence, memoranda, legal records, and printed matter. They help focus on such cases as well as issues relating to airline industry of the United States, water use law, and terrorism.
Administrative Information
Access
Box numbers 36, 122, and 138-139 are closed during the lifetime of Abraham D. Sofaer, the remainder of the collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography Note
1938 May 6 Born, Bombay (Mumbai), India
1956-1959 Served with United States Air Force
1959 Naturalized as a citizen of the United States
1962 Graduated magna cum laude in history, Yeshiva College, New York
1964-1965 Editor-in-Chief, New York Law Review
1965 LL.B cum laude (Root-Tilden scholar), New York University Passed the bar
1965-1966 Law clerk, J. Skelly Wright, U.S. Court of Appeals, Washington, D.C.
1966-1967 Law clerk, William J. Brennan Jr., U.S. Supreme Court, Washington, D.C.
1967-1969 Assistant U.S. Attorney, U.S. District Court, Southern District, New York City, New York
1969-1979 Professor of Law, Columbia University, New York City, New York
1974-1975 Meyer Professor of Law and Social Research, Columbia University
1975 Brainerd Currie lecturer, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina
1975-1976 Hearing Officer, New York Department of Environment Conservation
1976 Author, War, Foreign Affairs and Constitutional Power: The Origins
1976-1978 Member, Board of Directors, Citizens Union and Mobilization for Youth Legal Services
1979-1985 Adjunct Professor of Law, Columbia University
1979-1985 Judge, U.S District Court, Southern District of New York City, New York
1980 Doctor of Law, honoris causa, Yeshiva University, New York
1985 Author, The Political Offense and Terrorism and The United States and the World Court
1985-1990 Legal advisor, Department of State, Washington, D.C.
1986 Author, The War Powers Resolution and Antiterrorist Operations
1988 Author, The War Powers Resolution
1990 Distinguished Visiting Fellow, Hoover Institution, Stanford University
1990-1994 Practiced law with Hughes, Hubbard, and Reed, Washington, D.C.
1994- Senior Fellow and George P. Shultz Distinguished Scholar, Hoover Institution, Stanford University
1999 Author, The New Terror: Facing the Threat of Biological and Chemical Weapons
2001 Author, The Transnational Dimension of Cyber Crime and Terrorism
Scope and Content of Collection
The Abraham Sofaer papers illustrate his career and accomplishments as a legal advisor, an editor of Law Review, a professor, a judge, and a prolific writer. Includes information about his prominent legal cases, especially the libel suit against Time magazine brought by Ariel Sharon in 1984.
Abraham Sofaer's legal expertise and judicial opinions contained in this collection relate to international law and its interpretation, constitutional aspects of United States laws, defense programs, transportation issues, environmental conservation, and safety and security of the world community.
Materials include writings, reports, notes, studies, correspondence, memoranda, legal records, and printed matter. Documents bring to life the international laws of warfare, the presidential war-making powers in the United States, defense concerns, the legal interpretation of the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty, and the development of the Strategic Defense Initiative.
Transportation issues relate to airline industry in the United States. Polychlorinated biphenyls (PCB) and contamination of Upper Hudson River raised the issues of elimination of contamination, environmental conservation, water use law, and the need for developing a new approach to resolve environmental conflicts.
Terrorism is linked to the question of security and became an important part of his judicial proceedings. Even foreign countries like Korea, Libya, and Panama, and Nicaragua find their places in his courtroom.
His legal opinions and method of handling these issues reflect his expertise and contribution to the legal profession.
The original order of the collection has been maintained.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in Stanford University's online catalog.
Subjects
Sharon, Ariel.; United States. Dept. of State.; National Commission to Ensure a Strong Competitive Airline Industry(U.S.); Time, inc.; Strategic Defense Initiative.; Arms Control.; Nuclear weapons.; Airlines--United States.; Journalism--United States.; War (International law); International law.; War and emergency powers--United States.; Water--Law and legislation.; Antimissile missiles.; Israel.
Container List
- "Interpreting the ABM Treaty," Paul H. Nitze, 1987 (Folder 1: 1)
- "The ABM Treaty: Legal Analysis in Political Cauldron," Abraham D. Sofaer, The Washington Quarterly, 1987 (Folder 1: 2)
- ABM papers, 1985-1991 and undated (Folder 1: 3)
- ABM Treaty: Sofaer ABM interpretation, 1987 (Folder 1: 4)
- Miscellaneous materials about ABM Treaty (Box 2)
  - 1985-1994 (Folder 2: 1-8)
  - 1987-1993 (Folder 3: 1-8)
- ABM documents and legal issues relating to Supreme Court decision and international law, 1989-1994 and undated (Folder 4: 1-11)
- National Commission to Ensure a Strong Competitive Airline Industry, 1984-1994 (Box 5-7)
- Plaintiff and defendant's exhibits, 1977-1984. (Folder 8: 1-2)
  Sharon vs. Time case
- Polychlorinated Biphenyls - National Research Council report, 1979 (Folder 8: 3)
- Clippings
  - 1973-1984 (Folder 8: 4)
  - 1982 (Folder 9: 1)
- Legal records and related matters, 1984-1985 and undated (Folder 9: 2-3)
- Materials relating to the libel suit brought by Ariel Sharon against Time magazine, 1984 (Folder 10: 1-2)
- Writings by others, 1955-1978 (Folder 10: 3)
- Books and reports by others, 1955-1981. (Folder 11: 1)
  Includes 1 photographic print depicting Abraham Sofaer with his children, undated
- First Stage High Pressure Turbine Vane - Artifact, undated (Folder 11: 2)
- Book by Paul A. Samuelson, 1976 and an issue of a legal journal, 1984 (Folder 12: 1)
- Materials relating to Ariel Sharon's case against Time magazine
  - 1984 (Folder 12: 2)
  - 1984 and a book, 1950 (Folder 13: 1-3)
- Ariel Sharon - Case papers, 1984 (Box 14-19)
- Commission of Inquiry into the events at the refugee camps in Beirut – Final report, 1983 (Folder 20: 1)
- Time magazine, 1983 (Folder 20: 2)
- Ariel Sharon – Case papers, 1984 (Folder 20: 3-4)
- Ariel Sharon - Case papers (Box 21-22)
  - 1976-1982
  - 1982-1985 (Folder 23: 1-20)
- 1984 (Box 24)
- Articles by others, 1980-1983 (Folder 25: 1)
- Time magazine articles, 1982-1983 (Folder 25: 2)
- Notes, undated (Folder 25: 3)
- Legal records – Ariel Sharon vs. Time magazine, 1984
- Miscellaneous papers, 1969-1977. (Box 26)
  Includes materials relating to environmental conservation and polychlorinated biphenyls, legal records, writings by others, and related materials
- Engineering report, 1971-1976. (Box 27)
  Includes a photographic print from New York Environment Conservation, undated
- Report on wastewater monitoring program, 1975-1976 (Box 28)
- Papers relating to issues of environmental conservation, and related matters, 1969-1976 (Box 29)
- Department of Environmental Conservation, State of New York
  - 1975 November-December (Box 30)
  - 1975 October – 1976 April (Box 31)
  - 1976 April-May (Box 32)
- Department of Environmental Conservation, issues of wastewater management, and utilization of various toxic substances, 1976 (Box 33)
- Materials relating to monitoring of PCB in fish, and legal papers about General Electric, environmental conservation, 1971-1976 (Box 34)
  SEE ALSO Box 152
- Department of Environmental Conservation, 1975 (Folder 35: 1)
- Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1973 (Folder 35: 2)
- Environmental Protection Agency – Transcript proceedings, 1974 (Folder 35: 3)
- Polychlorinated Biphenyls and the Environment – Interdepartmental Task Force on PCBs, Washington, D.C., 1972 May (Folder 35: 4)
- Operation report on "Shin Kai: The Pneuma Dredge," Shiro Kasajima, undated (Folder 35: 5)
- Photocopy of an article on "Waterfowl and Wetlands," and Feener and Steiger Seafoods, Inc., undated (Folder 35: 6)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1973-1976 (Folder 35: 7)
- Box closed during the lifetime of Abraham D. Sofaer (Box 36)
- Ariel Sharon – Case papers, 1983-1985 (Box 37)
- Legal documents relating to Ariel Sharon and other cases, 1977-1985 (Box 38-39)
  - 1982-1985 (Box 40)
  - 1984-1985. (Box 41)
    Includes a book on Israel's Lebanon War
  - 1979-1985 (Box 42)
  - 1977-1985 and undated (Box 43)
    Includes an unidentified photographic print
  - 1980-1984 (Box 44)
  - 1984 (Box 45-47)
- Legal documents vs. City of New York, 1980-1983 (Box 48)
- Case of Ariel Sharon vs. Time, 1984-1985 (Box 49)
- Miscellany, 1961-1989 and undated. (Box 50)
  Includes correspondence, memoranda, note, printed matter, and writings by others
- Notes, undated; proceedings of the Ditchley Foundations Conference, 1987 February 27-March 1 (Folder 51: 1)
- Articles, issues of law journals, and printed matter, 1961-1987 and undated (Folder 51: 2-3)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to allocation of power and testimony, 1967-1973 (Folder 51: 4)
- "International Law and the Action of the United States in Panama." (Folder 51: 5-7)
  Includes related materials about General Noriega and Panama, 1988-1990 and undated
- Soviet law, 1986-1994 (Folder 52: 1)
- "Adjudication in the International Court of Justice: Progress through Realism," and related materials, 1989-1992 (Folder 52: 2-3)
- Law of Naval Warfare Symposium on Targeting Enemy Merchant Shipping, 1990 February 1-3; JAG Symposium, 1989; handbook of naval operations; and related materials (Box 53)
- Papers relating to Mahan Centennial Conference Attendees, April 29-May 1, 1990, and courses and syllabus of the United States Naval War College, Rhode Island, 1989-1990 (Folder 54: 1-3)
- The War Powers Resolution, Washington, D.C., 1988 (Folder 55: 1)
- Printed matter, 1988-1994 (Folder 55: 2)
- Materials concerning requests for confidential executive branch information, 1982-1989. (Folder 55: 3)
  Includes address and printed matter, 1957-1982
- Testimony on War Powers Resolution and related documents, 1984-1995 and undated (Folder 55: 4)
- The War Powers Resolution, Washington, D.C., 1988 (Folder 56: 1)
- War Powers resolution and its applications, 1933-1988 (Folder 56: 2-4)
- The National Resources Defense Council's (NRDC) efforts to eliminate Polychlorinated Biphenyls (PCB) contamination and PCB hot spot dredging program for Upper Hudson River, New York, 1980-1987. (Folder 57: 1-2)
  Includes materials relating to development of new approaches to deal with environmental conflict
- Conference proceedings – National Conference on Polychlorinated Biphenyls, Chicago, Illinois, 1975 November 19-21; 1976 (Folder 57: 3)
- Water – Miscellaneous, 1952-1997 (Folder 58: 1-2)
- Water contracts, 1974-1995 (Folder 58: 3)
- Law Review articles, 1984-1989 (Folder 58: 4)
- California meeting, Los Angeles, 1995 June 28 (Folder 59: 1)
- Elizabeth (Betsy) Ann Rieke, 1984-1992 (Folder 59: 2)
- Arizona Water Bank proposal, 1994 (Folder 59: 3)
- Amnesty agreement between the Central Arizona Water Conservation District and the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California, 1994 (Folder 59: 4)
- Bureau of Reclamation, 1995 (Folder 59: 5)
- All-American Canal Construction Contract (Boulder Canyon) Project, 1934 (Folder 59: 6)
- ACWA Conference – Milt Nathanson's speech, San Diego, California, 1985 (Folder 59: 7)
- Notes and papers on water, 1995-1997 (Folder 59: 8)
- Water materials, 1997-1998 (Folder 59: 9)
- San Luis Rey, 1996 (Folder 60: 1)
- San Diego meeting, 1995 July 6-7 (Folder 60: 2)
- San Diego Water Authority, 1996-1997 (Folder 60: 3)
- Romney, Clyde A. and Sterling, 1996 (Folder 60: 4)
- Phoenix meeting, 1995 June 8 (Folder 60: 5)
- Nevada meeting, 1995 June 22 (Folder 60: 6)
- Newspaper articles, 1994-1997 (Folder 60: 7)
- Metropolitan Water District, 1996 (Folder 60: 8)
- Horton, Knox, Carter and Foote, 1996 (Folder 60: 9)
- Glenn, Wright, Jacobs and Schell, 1996 (Folder 60: 10)
- Fredericks, Pelcyger, Hester and White, 1996 (Folder 60: 11)
- Environmental protection issues, 1995 (Folder 60: 12)
- Department of Water and Power, 1996-1997 (Folder 60: 13)
- Colorado River Board of California, 1996-1997 (Folder 60: 14)
- Reliability, 1995 (Folder 61: 1)
- Technical Committee (TC) meeting, Palo Alto, California, 1995 July 20 (Folder 61: 2)
- Progress reports nos. 1-4 – Colorado River Lower Basin Technical Committee, 1995 (Folder 61: 3)
- Environmental Defense Fund, 1996 (Folder 61: 4)
- Palo Verde Fallowing program, 1992 (Folder 61: 5)
- Colorado River Water Users Association, 1995 (Folder 61: 6)
- "California and Colorado-River Water: Seize the Opportunity,", 1997 (Folder 61: 7)
- Vista Irrigation District, 1996 (Folder 61: 8)
- Technical Committee reports, 1995 (Folder 61: 9)
- Taylor letter, 1996 (Folder 61: 10)
- Testimony of Gerald Zimmerman, source materials on Metropolitan Water District Act Section 35, 1995, and law journal, 1988 (Folder 61: 11)
- Coachella Valley Water District, 1996 (Folder 62: 1)
- Arizona letter, 1995 (Folder 62: 2)
- Agreement for services of independent contractor between the Colorado River Commission of the State of Nevada and Abraham Sofaer, 1995 (Folder 62: 3)
- Proposed regulations and related materials, 1994-1995 (Folder 62: 4)
- The Salton Sea, undated (Folder 62: 5)
- Tribal rights, undated (Folder 62: 6)
- Department of the Interior and proposed Colorado River regulations, 1991-1994 (Folder 62: 7)
- Central Arizona Project (CAP) Principles of Agreement, 1995 (Folder 62: 8)
- Department of the Interior and the Central Arizona Project financial restructuring issue, 1995 (Folder 62: 9)
- Central Arizona Project (CAP) negotiations, 1995 (Folder 62: 10)
- Abraham Sofaer – Rosenberg International Forum on Water Policy, 1997 (Folder 62: 11)
- Rate refinement process, 1996 (Folder 62: 12)
- Miscellany, 1994-1997. (Folder 62: 13)
  Water, water rights, and flood management issues
- Imperial Irrigation District, 1995-1996 (Folder 63: 1)
- Coachella Valley Water District, 1993 (Folder 63: 2)
- Metropolitan Water District of Southern California/Imperial/ Palo Verde/Coachella – Approval agreement, 1989 (Folder 63: 3)
- Coachella Valley Water District, undated (Folder 63: 4)
- Background notebook for Abraham Sofaer – Nevada, 1993-1994 (Folder 63: 5)
- Water expenses, 1995-1997 (Folder 63: 6-8)
- Expenses and invoices, 1996 (Folder 63: 9)
- Bureau of Reclamation meeting, Boulder, Colorado, undated (Folder 63: 10)
- Palo Verde Irrigation District, 1996 (Folder 64: 1)
- Arizona vs. California (Supreme Court) – Report of the Special Master, 1960 (Folder 64: 2)
- Metropolitan District – Cooling water for power plants, 1994 (Folder 64: 3)
- Yuma District – Information booklet, 1995 (Folder 64: 4)
- United States Supreme Court water cases, 1962-1963 and undated (Folder 64: 5)
- Imperial tech report – On-farm Irrigation Efficiency, 1994 (Folder 64: 6)
- Imperial-Coachella Agreement, 1934 (Folder 64: 7)
- Imperial Irrigation District – Alleged Waste and Unreasonable Use of Water - Water Decision 1600, 1984 (Folder 64: 8)
- Imperial/Metropolitan Water Conservation Program, 1989 (Folder 64: 9)
- Coachella – Water Transfer Legislation, 1992 (Folder 64: 10)
- Coachella and Bureau of Reclamation – Memorandum of Agreement, undated (Folder 64: 11)
- Coachella – Proposed Land Fallowing Agreement and Test Water Savings, 1993 and undated (Folder 64: 12)
- Barry Goldwater, 1954-1983 (Folder 65: 1)
- Angola, Tonkin, 1964 (Folder 65: 2)
- War Power notes, 1968 and undated (Folder 65: 3)
- Correspondence, 1973-1978 (Folder 65: 4)
- Reviews of Abraham D. Sofaer's War, Foreign Affairs and Constitutional Power, 1977-1978 (Folder 65: 5)
- American Interventions in the Nineteenth Century, undated (Folder 65: 6)
- Articles and remark by others on War Powers, 1988 and undated (Folder 65: 7)
- "The War Powers Debacle" and "Separation of Powers and the Use of Force,", undated (Folder 65: 8)
- Nunn-Byrd-Warner proposal on War Powers, 1988 (Folder 65: 9)
- Reconstruction – The Congressional Globe, undated (Folder 65: 10)
- Cuba - Article, undated (Folder 65: 11)
- Printed matter, 1973-1986 (Folder 65: 12)
- Emergency powers (Box 66)
  - Articles by others, 1941-1978 (Folder 66: 1)
  - "Emergency Power and the Hero of New Orleans,", 1978. (Folder 66: 2)
    Article
- Correspondence regarding Andrew Jackson's speech, 1973-1979. (Folder 66: 3)
  Includes 4 photographic prints depicting Abraham Sofaer and other unidentified individuals, 1978-1979
- Clippings and printed matter, 1970-1991 (Folder 66: 4)
- Notes, undated (Folder 66: 5)
- "The War Powers Debacle,", undated (Folder 66: 6)
- Legal documents, 1936-1991 (Folder 66: 7)
- Articles by others, 1984-1988 (Folder 66: 8)
- Miscellany, 1972-1984 (Folder 66: 9)
- United States and South Korea, 1947-1949 (Folder 67: 1)
- Separation of powers, 1970-1976 (Folder 67: 2)
- War Powers study, 1971-1982 and undated (Folder 67: 3-6)
- "Emergency Power and the Hero of New Orleans,", undated (Folder 68: 1)
- New York Court of Appeals, 1983 (Folder 68: 2)
- Thomas Jefferson - Article by Gerhard Casper, 1995 (Folder 68: 3)
- Writings by others, 1972-1980 (Folder 68: 4-5)
- Miscellany, 1983 (Folder 68: 6)
- Chadha, 1982-1989 (Folder 69: 1)
- War Powers Resolution and papers, 1971-1980 (Folder 69: 2-3)
- Writings by others and study, 1939-1982 (Folder 69: 4)
- Miscellany, 1972 (Folder 68: 5)
- Tyler memos, 1972-1978 (Folder 70: 1)
- War Power, 1967-1983 (Folder 70: 2)
- Message to Congress from President Van Buren, 1837-1838 (Folder 70: 3)
- Summaries of Congressional Proceedings – Administration of Andrew Jackson (1830-1836), 1978 and undated (Folder 70: 4)
- Clipping and legal documents including case between Ronald Reagan and Michael L. Lowry, 1987-1994 (Folder 70: 5)
- Tyler – Summaries, 1978 and undated (Folder 71: 1)
- Van Buren, 1837-1841 (Folder 71: 2)
- Clippings and notes, 1985 and undated (Folder 71: 3)
- Peter McColough – Article, 1979 (Folder 71: 4)
- Proceedings of Congressional sessions, 1974-1979 (Folder 71: 5)
- Correspondence, 1984-1988 (Folder 71: 6)
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 71: 7)
- Writings of Abraham Sofaer, circa 1970-1971. "The War Powers Debacle," undated; Realizing Social Ideals through Law," 1970, and "The Change of Status Adjudication: A Case Study of the Informal Agency Process," (Folder 72: 1)
- Legal and financial case documents, 1988 and undated (Folder 72: 2)
- Printed matter, 1972-1983 (Folder 72: 3)
- Miscellany, 1988-1991 (Folder 72: 4)
- Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Folder 73: 1)
- Clippings and notes, 1983-1990 and undated (Folder 73: 2)
- "Sentencing: Lessons from the Bible," Abraham Sofaer, 1984; remarks at the commencement exercises of Yeshiva University, New York, 1980; "No Rent for Rats: An Analysis of the City Bar Proposal," with Franklin S. Bonem; and "The Industrial Democracies and the World Economy," remarks of Abraham Sofaer, 1986 (Folder 73: 3)
- Printed matter – Articles by Abraham Sofaer and others, Supreme Court reports, and an article by Philip B. Kurland, 1952-1994 (Folder 73: 4)
- Business financial statements, 1990-1993 (Folder 73: 5)
- Writings by others, 1989 and undated (Folder 73: 6)
- Miscellany, 1988-1993 and undated (Folder 73: 7)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1976-1993 (Folder 74: 1)
- Miscellany, 1978-1992 (Folder 74: 2-4)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1973-1991 (Folder 75: 1)
- Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Folder 75: 2)
- "Treaty Interpretation: A Comment,", 1989 (Folder 75: 3)
- Congressional records, 1975-1991 (Folder 75: 4)
- Reports and seminar proceedings, 1983-1985 and undated (Folder 75: 5)
- War Power seminar, undated (Folder 75: 6)
- Miscellany, 1984 (Folder 75: 7)
- Allocation of Powers, 1968-1973 (Folder 76: 1)
- "War Powers - Wilson: Confusions and Crises, 1915-1916," Arthur S. Link, 1964 (Folder 76: 2)
- Writings by others, 1971-1985 (Folder 76: 3)
- Printed matter, 1934-1984 (Folder 76: 4-5)
- Executive Privilege, 1961-1977. (Folder 77: 1-3)
  Includes Abraham Sofaer's "Raoul Berger's Executive Privilege: A Constitutional Myth – A Critical Essay," undated
- Robert William Russell thesis presentation, 1967 (Folder 78: 1)
- Executive Privilege, 1961-1976 and undated (Folder 78: 2-3)
- Jacksonian drafts, 1979 and undated (Folder 79: 1)
- Veto power, undated (Folder 79: 2)
- Quallah Battov (Sumatra), 1831-1832. (Folder 79: 3)
  Photocopies and research article, 1980
- War Power papers, (1851), 1973-1993 (Folder 79: 4-5)
- Material Post, 1829 (Folder 80: 1)
- Executive Journal notes, undated (Folder 80: 2)
- Reactions to War, Foreign Affairs and Constitutional Power, volumes I and II, 1960-1978 (Folder 80: 3-4)
- Writings by others, 1967-1994 (Folder 80: 5)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1967-1983 (Folder 80: 6)
- Legal records, 1975 (Folder 80: 7)
- Miscellany, 1976-1980 (Folder 80: 8)
- Polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs), 1990 (Folder 81: 1)
- Ariel Sharon, 1985-1986 and undated (Folder 81: 2)
- Judicial reviews, 1968-1974 (Folder 81: 3)
- Writings and remarks by others, 1987-1988 and undated (Folder 81: 4)
- Address, articles, remarks, and statement by Abraham Sofaer, 1976-1988 (Folder 81: 5-6)
- Ariel Sharon vs. Time – Defense exhibits, 1984 (Folder 82: 1)
- Westmoreland CBS libel trail – Clippings, 1984-1985 (Folder 82: 2)
- Legal records and related materials, 1979-1983 (Folder 82: 3)
- Journals, 1985 (Folder 82: 4)
- Legal Advisor - remarks before the Bar Association, security clearance, testimonies before various Senate Committees on different subjects, presentation of portrait of Judge J. Skelly Wright's portrait, and statements on U.S.-U.K. Extradition Treaty, 1985 (Folder 83: 1-14)
- Speeches, statements, testimonies on terrorism, economic sanctions, crime, arms control before Senate Subcommittees relating to various issues, 1985-1986 (Folder 84: 1-14)